Guide to the Amos B. Stanton papers, 1843-1930
Stanton, Amos B. papers, 1843-1930
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Amos B. Stanton papers, 1843-1930
4265
Amos B. Stanton, d. 1864
.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, documents, clippings, publications, diaries.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Primarily Civil War letters from Stanton to his wife. Also, family letters, certificates, pension files, clippings, publications, and diaries of John Crosby and Amos B. Stanton.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Amos B. Stanton of Adrian, N.Y. (Steuben County) served as a 1st lieutenant in the 86th Regiment, New York Volunteers, an Elmira, N.Y. regiment. He was killed at Petersburg on June 16, 1864.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Primarily Civil War letters from Stanton to his wife. Also, family letters, certificates, pension files, clippings, publications, and diaries of John Crosby and Amos B. Stanton.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Stanton, Amos B., d. 1864.; Stanton family.; Crosby, John.; United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 86th (1861-1865).
Subjects:
Family--New York (State)--Steuben County.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Boxes 1-2
Series II. Papers
Box 2
Series III. Volumes
Box 2
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - 1843, 1851-1857 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1861 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - January-February 1862 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - March-May 1862 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - June-July 1862 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - August-September 1862 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - October-December 1862 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - January-March 1863 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - April-May 1863 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - June-July 1863 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - August 1863 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - October-November 1863 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - December 1863 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - January-March 1864 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - April-May 1864 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - June-September, November 1864 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - ca. 1861-1864 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1865-1869 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1870-1871 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1872 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1873-1876 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1881, 1930, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series II. Papers
  - Certificates: S. Council, 1854 Marriage Certificate, 1854 Military Appointment, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Copy of Stanton pension application file (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Copy of Stanton's military service record (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Copy of Burial List (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pamphlet: National Cemeteries of the Richmond Area (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Indenture: Preston-Ordway, Steuben County, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - News clippings (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Photograph from A. B. Stanton Diary, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Constitution, By-laws, and Rules of Order of Canisteo Mountain Lodge, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 2 booklets: Rebellion Record, ca. 1862; Toby and the Wasp, 1883 (advertising Piso's cure) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Scrap of Collar from a Confederate Officer's Coat (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Object is described in a letter dated May 29, 1864 (Folder 2-2)
  - Diary of J. B. Crosby, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series III. Volumes
  - Diary: John Crosby, 1854 (Box 2)
  - Diary: Amos B. Stanton, 1863 (Box 2)
  - Diary: Amos B. Stanton, 1864 (Box 2)
  - Diary: Crosby?, 1871 (Box 2)